CURRICULUM VITAE



Name: Morteza MOOZIRI
Date of Birth: Dec 29, 1996
Affiliation: Department of Brain
and Cognitive Sciences, Royan
Institute for Stem Cell Biology and
Technology, ACECR, Tehran, Iran.

⊠ m.mooziri@royaninstitute.org ⊠ mortezamooziri@gmail.com

% +98 917 695 0612

Homepage | Google Scholar LinkedIn | GitHub

Last Update: Sep 13, 2024

"Studying medicine made my background heavy in physiology. In my research, I would like to learn how the macro- and micro-circuits within the mammalian brain perform computations necessary to process and utilize information. I'm interested in using high-resolution neurophysiological methods, computational techniques, and deep neural networks to unravel the mysteries of brain. Standing at the interface of biology, clinic, computational neuroscience, and artificial intelligence is very well-aligned with a long-term plan of finding solutions to neural disabilities of humans. I am eagerly looking forward to learning more and making collaborations to advance out understanding of brain."

EDUCATION

Sep 2015 - Jan 2023 M.D., Medicine

School of Medicine, Zahedan University of Medical Sciences (ZAUMS),

Zahedan, Iran (GPA = 3.61/4)

Sep 2012 - Sep 2015 Diploma, Biological Sciences
Imam Sadeq High School, Lamerd, Iran (GPA = 4/4)

WORKSHOP and CERTIFICATE

Computational Neuroscience Summer Course Neuromatch Academy,

Virtual Event | Jul 2022 | Certificate

Computational Neuroscience Sadra Neuroscience Association,

Virtual Event | Jun-Aug 2021

Cognitive Neuroscience Sadra Neuroscience Association,

Virtual Event | Oct-Dec 2020

EXPERIENCE

Research

Jul 2023 - present Research Assistant

Department of Brain and Cognitive Sciences, Cell Science Research Center, Royan Institute for Stem Cell Biology and Technology, ACECR, Tehran, Iran

- Monkey neurophysiology: recording neuronal activity and LFP from Inferior Temporal and Ventrolateral Prefrontal Cortices
- Studying cortical computations underlying visual processing
- Output: see Publication > Preprint > Mooziri et al., In Prep., 2024a

Jun 2020 - Dec 2022 Research Assistant

Laboratory Animals Research Center, ZAUMS, Zahedan, Iran

- Set up a rodent electrophysiology lab (first time at ZAUMS)
- Rodent behavior and neurophysiology: study LFP activities underlying memory and anxiety in rodents
- Output: see Publication > Journal Article > Mooziri et al., Sci. Rep., 2024

Teaching

Jul 2024 Project TA

Computational Neuroscience Summer Course

Neuromatch Academy (NMA) | Virtual Event | Certificate

- <u>Description</u>
- I've led several projects with students from USA, UK, Iran, Germany, China, India, Turkey, etc.

Jul 2023 Regular TA

Computational Neuroscience Summer Course

Neuromatch Academy (NMA) | Virtual Event | Certificate

• I've led students from Iran, India, and USA.

PROJECT

Jul 2023 - present Visual object recognition in macaque inferior temporal and ventrolateral prefrontal cortices

Royan Institute, ACECR, Tehran, Iran.

- Roles: Data Collection, Data Analysis, Writing
- Output: see Publication > Preprint > Mooziri et al., In Prep., 2024a

Jun 2020 - Dec 2022 Evaluation of the functional connectivity between olfactory bulb and prefrontal cortex during anxiety behavior in rat

Laboratory Animals Research Center, ZAUMS, Zahedan, Iran.

- Roles: Surgery, Data Collection, Data Analysis, Writing
- Output: see Publication > Journal Article > Mooziri et al., Sci. Rep., 2024

PUBLICATION (\$ denotes co-first authors)

Preprint

- 2024a *Mooziri* *, Zare *, Qolami, Javan, Shakerian, & Dehaqani
 Semantic processing in primate ventral visual stream and machines | In Prep.
- 2024b *Mooziri*, Samii Moghaddam, & Bahmani
 Distinct tuning properties of human hippocampal neuronal sub-populations encode working memory | In Prep.

Journal Article (Peer-reviewed)

- 2024 Mooziri*, Samii Moghaddam*, Mirshekar, & Raoufy
 Olfactory bulb-medial prefrontal cortex theta synchronization is associated with anxiety |
 Scientific Reports
- 2023 Dehdar, Mooziri, Samii Moghaddam, Salimi M, Nazari, Dehghan, Jamaati, Salimi A, & Raoufy Corticosteroid treatment attenuates anxiety and mPFC-amygdala circuit dysfunction in allergic asthma | Life Sciences
- 2022 Gholami-Mahtaj, Mooziri, Bamdad, Mikaili, Jamaati, & Raoufy

 Neural signature of attention impairment in allergic asthma: an ERP study | International Journal of Neuroscience

Gholami-Mahtaj, **Mooziri**, Dehdar, Abdolsamadi, Salimi, & Raoufy

ACC-BLA functional connectivity disruption in allergic inflammation is associated with anxiety

| Scientific Reports

INVITED TALK

- On the mysteries of neural space | Lecture series

 Neuromodulation Lab, Department of Physiology, Tarbiat Modares University, Tehran, Iran
- 2023 Principles of deep brain recording
 Student Research Committee, ZAUMS, Zahedan, Iran

RESOURCE

2024 Visual episodic memory task | Github Repository

Description: Matlab scripts and functions for a visual episodic memory task in human, implemented in PsychToolbox.

RESEARCH INTEREST

Systems/Computational/Cognitive Neuroscience Neurophysiological and computational

foundations of brain function and behavior, esp. for working memory, attention, and visual

perception

Neural Coding Information processing mechanisms by neurons

and circuits, esp. population coding and latent dynamics of population activity as well as local and long-range connectivity of neurons and

oscillations

NeuroAl Using artificial intelligence to model/explain brain

phenomena, esp. deep neural networks

Theory Using theoretical frameworks to describe brain

function and behavior, e.g., Bayesian framework

SKILL

Computational

Programming MATLAB

Description: Advanced programming skills

Toolboxes: Chronux, PsychToolbox

Python

Description: Advanced programming skills

Libraries: Numpy, Pandas, PyTorch, Scikit-learn, SciPy, Matplotlib,

Seaborn, etc

Artificial Intelligence Machine Learning

Description: Intermediate-to-advanced knowledge and skills in MATLAB

and python, for classification, clustering, and regression purposes

Deep Learning

Description: Intermediate-to-advanced knowledge and skills in Python

(using PyTorch), esp. for CNNs and RNNs

Mathematics Linear Algebra

Description: Intermediate knowledge

Neural Data Analysis Advanced knowledge and skills in MATLAB

Experience in working with neurophysiological data of <u>rat</u> (Mooziri et al., Sci. Rep., 2024), <u>monkey</u> (Mooziri et al., In Prep., 2024a), & <u>human</u> (Mooziri et al., In Prep., 2024b)

• LFP: Time-frequency domain transformation; Regional activity; Functional connectivity; Directionality analysis

- Spiking activity: Single-neuron rate and temporal coding; Population coding; Directionality analysis
- General: Machine learning, Information theory & Signal detection theory

Theoretical Neuroscience

Computational and Intermediate knowledge and skills in Python

- Modeling electrical properties of neurons and microcircuits
- Dealing with high-dimensional data

Data Science Advanced knowledge and skills in working with public datasets of neurophysiology

See Mooziri et al., In Prep., 2024b

Behavioral Data Analysis Intermediate-to-advanced knowledge and skills in MATLAB/Python

General metrics, e.g., anxiety index, d-prime, etc (Rat, Monkey, Human data)

Statistics Intermediate knowledge and skills in Graphpad Prism, MATLAB, and Python

Lab (only those with advanced experience)

Rat Handling

Stereotaxic Brain Surgery Behavioral Data Acquisition

Electrophysiological Data Acquisition

Monkey Handling

Electrophysiological Data Acquisition Functional Brain Mapping with DBS

Other

English Full Professional Proficiency

Advanced Communication Skills

Scientific Writing Advanced skills

Tools Adobe Illustrator

Description: Intermediate skills for data visualizations

Soft Skills Scientific vision

Leadership Group work

VALUE

Respect Ambition

Cooperation-Teamwork

Responsiveness

Openness to Experience

HOBBY

Explore Scientific Community (Journals, Science

News, etc.)

Watch Movie (Sci-fi, Sitcom, Documentary,

Astronomical, Drama)

Sports (Soccer, Ping-pong)

Play Video Games

REFERENCE

Mohammad Reza Raoufy Associate Professor, Department of Physiology, Faculty of Medical

Sciences, Tarbiat Modares University, Tehran, Iran

Mohammad-Reza A. Dehagani Assistant Professor, School of Electrical and Computer Engineering,

University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran

Zahra Bahmani Assistant Professor, Department of Biomedical Engineering, Faculty

of Electrical & Computer Engineering, Tarbiat Modares University,

Tehran, Iran